<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.munirrani.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://www.munirrani.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-10-26T03:52:14+00:00</updated><id>https://www.munirrani.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Munir&apos;s portfolio and blog site </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Preservation and Death of Knowledge</title><link href="https://www.munirrani.com/blog/2023/the-preservation-and-death-of-knowledge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Preservation and Death of Knowledge"/><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.munirrani.com/blog/2023/the-preservation-and-death-of-knowledge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.munirrani.com/blog/2023/the-preservation-and-death-of-knowledge/"><![CDATA[<p>When reflecting upon the relation of knowledge with streams of human history, we can gain recognition on the significance of preserving it and the consequence of its death.</p> <p>To use an analogy, the situation of knowledge preserved is akin to a crowd hand wave. Imagine you are standing in a large crowd during a sports event and you are anticipating a hand wave from a distance. You would be raising your own hands in celebration only when the wave is reaching near you, as others surrounding within your crowd would do.</p> <p>An active knowledge in a historical timescale is the continuous wave of the crowd. We can perceive that a wave traversing on the timescale, represents knowledge that human collectively possess. As the wave moves further along, one generation receives it and carries on to the next. One aspect of an ideal situation is all knowledge are to be preserved, imagined by the wave from the past able to arrive at the present. However in reality, it is not the case as some if not many did not pass forward to today. Another aspect of the ideal situation is all humans living in a concurrent timeframe could consolidate all knowledge, that the wave is conceived of the same. Though in actuality, it tends to be bounded by civilizational hubs, where the waves differ in locality.</p> <p>The cause of death of knowledge is not necessarily due to the loss of written manuscripts, books, essays, and other intellectual materials alike, even though they contribute to its preservation. Instead, the death of knowledge is only when a human, especially scholars who possess it, have left this world while none others managed to gain it to be preserved and transmitted, and when no person in the future studies it.</p> <p>Using the perspective of human psychology on its metaphysics <sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, this death is due to knowledge <em>(‘ilm)</em> manifested in this universe <em>(‘ālam)</em> possessible only by a human. Humans termed as a rational being <em>(al-ḥayawān al-nāṭiq)</em>, is both body and soul, having physical and spiritual dual natures at once. The spiritual power for cognition, conducted through the mind <em>(‘aql)</em> mainly for reasoning, and the heart <em>(qalb)</em> for faith, is governed by its rational articulate soul <em>(nafs al-nāṭiqah)</em>. This rational soul, as a special power gifted only to humans and none other corporeal beings, is responsible for the process of intellection, gaining the knowledge. It endows them the ability to utilize language, perform abstraction and judgement, and obtain true meaning. From here, we can imply the loss of a learned soul to the loss of knowledge, effecting its preservation, and that it is alive in so far as there exists them embodying it.</p> <p>It is hence a societal need for an inborn generation, who enters the world on a clean slate to its innate nature <em>(fiṭrah)</em>, throughout their life, to embody important knowledge of the past and the present such that it is carried ahead. Knowledge from a predecessor thus have to be relearned by its successors through proper means of education. Failure to do so would spell its future demise.</p> <p>The important knowledge in question is that of truth. Truth is singular, eternal, and immutable; it remains unchanged throughout time. Similarly in the opposite way, unimportant knowledge is those that is the fabrication of truth i.e falsity; they decay to irrelevancy due to contradictions. Thus, the strive for important knowledge is the strive for truth.</p> <p>By using a crowd hand wave analogy for knowledge transmission, and relating it to the human soul owning the sole power of possessing knowledge, we can identify how it would preserve or die throughout history.</p> <hr/> <p><br/> References:</p> <div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"> <ol> <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote"> <p>The Nature Of Man And The Psychology Of The Human Soul <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p> </li> </ol> </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When reflecting upon the relation of knowledge with streams of human history, we can gain recognition on the significance of preserving it and the consequence of its death.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Developing an NFT Marketplace Mobile App with React Native, IPFS &amp;amp; Ethereum</title><link href="https://www.munirrani.com/blog/2022/developing-nft-marketplace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developing an NFT Marketplace Mobile App with React Native, IPFS &amp;amp; Ethereum"/><published>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.munirrani.com/blog/2022/developing-nft-marketplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.munirrani.com/blog/2022/developing-nft-marketplace/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="tech"/><category term="code"/><category term="blockchain"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A hackathon journey of building an NFT mobile application in React Native, IPFS & Ethereum.]]></summary></entry></feed>